

# AVINASH DHUMAL

Engineering Manager

# **CONTACT INFO**



+91-779-840-6759



avinash\_dhumal@yahoo.com



Pune, MH, India

#### ONLINE PRESENCE



LinkedIn Profile



Online Profile



medium.com blog



Hacker Rank Profile

## ABOUT ME

Experienced **Technical People Manager** with **13.3+ years** in software **management, architecture, design, development, and support**. Led and managed client, database, and enterprise applications using the **Microsoft Technology** stack in both **Azure and AWS** Cloud environments, as well as noncloud environments.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Last 3)

### **Engineering Manager**

R1 RCM, Inc. | FEB 2023 - PRESENT



- Orchestrated and managed two dynamic Scrum teams, each comprising over
   16+ members, to develop two critical healthcare products.
- Led an initiative to reduce manual touch for operators during patient
  appointment, resulting in a cost reduction of \$550,000 and an improved patient
  experience.
- Streamlined post-discharge workflows by centralizing patient information, saving \$100,000 in costs.
- Successfully migrated the Patient Communication Platform to Genesys
   PureCloud using Azure cloud and .NET Core technologies, delivering \$270,000 in
- Acted as a bridge between technology and business, aligning technical solutions with overarching business goals and strategies for success.
- Pioneering performance reviews, mentoring programs, and ongoing guidance to nurture a high-performing team, promoting professional growth, and fostering a culture of continuous improvement.
- Demonstrating effective resource allocation and budget management,
   optimizing resource utilization to consistently deliver projects on time and within budget constraints.

# **Associate Manager - IT**

PITNEY BOWES, INC. | FEB 2020 - FEB 2023



- Achieved significant cost savings of over \$1M+ by efficiently managing and migrating applications and data from on-premises environments to the AWS Cloud platform across more than 20 countries.
- Spearheaded Tier3 and DLA product operations and automation initiatives on a global scale.
- Architected the PBots Self Service portal, a transformative solution for automating operational activities.
- Led the development of the T3Online product using agile methodologies, fostering a collaborative and adaptable environment for successful product delivery.
- Consistently **improved security (vulnerability)** with a remarkable reduction in the Rapid 7 security score from 10+ to 1+.
- Additionally, skilfully managed and mentored a team of 11 engineers (direct),
   overseeing their performance, growth, and development.

# **SKILLS**

#### **TECHNOLOGIES**

.NET	.NET Core	MVC	C#
VB.NET	Web API	SQL Server	Windows Services
WCF	Web Services	HTML5 / CSS3	Bootstrap Design
jQuery	Angular JS	Angular	TypeScript
Vue JS			

#### **TOOLS**

TFS	GitLab	Jira	Azure DevOps
Service Now	Remedy	Pager Duty	Jenkins
MS Projects	MS Visio	Wireframe Sketcher	Lucid Charts
Checkmarks	Confluence	X-Ray	Postman

#### **CLOUD PLATFORMS**

Azure AWS Cloud Migration

## **LEADERSHIP & MANAGEMENT**

Team	Mentoring/Coaching	Conflict	Decision
Leader		Mgmt.	Making
Problem	Product Mgmt.	Project	Risk
Solving		Mgmt.	Mgmt.
Resource Mgmt.	Technical Expertise		

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (Last 3)

## **Assistant Manager - IT**

FLEX | JUN 2015 - FEB 2020



- Accomplished 3 major software releases and over 50 successful sprints in a 5year tenure, demonstrating consistent delivery excellence.
- Led and optimized automated order processing (EDI) operations, contributing to a substantial revenue stream of approximately \$10 million.
- Orchestrated a pivotal major release in FY 2018-19 for procurement department, resulting in an impressive ROI surpassing \$110 million, showcasing strategic leadership and financial acumen.
- Excelled as a Scrum Master, overseeing a proficient team of 6 direct reports,
   driving Agile projects using Azure DevOps, and excelling in KRA management,
   annual goal setting, and performance appraisals.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Engineering - I.T.**

**Pune University** 

JULY 2010

65.13 %

#### Diploma - I.T.

MSBTE, Mumbai

JUNE 2007

70.17 %

S. S. C.

Pune Vidyapeeth

JUNE 2004

72.80 %

# **AWARDS**

Star Award R1 RCM, Inc.

Ace Award
Pitney Bowes, Inc.

Star Award
Pitney Bowes, Inc.

Gateway - The leaders League flex

**Titanium Award** flex

Platinum Award

Spot Award L&T Infotect

Ace Award
Hexaware Technologies

To view my full accomplishments – more than decade + professional experience, <u>Click here</u> to view my online portfolio.